Nadav Vilder

(510) 379-8530 · Berkeley, CA · nadavilder@gmail.com github.com/nadavilder · linkedin.com/in/nadavilder Authorized To Work (Green Card)

Dedicated Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience developing web applications using modern languages and frameworks. **Led the development of the Siemens Application Lifecycle Management app**, supporting Agile methodologies and collaboration. Enthusiastic about making a difference and contributing to growth in a dynamic role. Open to remote/hybrid/office-only roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C# (Object Oriented Programming), Java
- Web Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- Databases: AWS (S3), SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Apache Lucene
- Tools and Methods: Agile, Git, GitLab, Docker, CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Polarion team, Siemens Digital Industries Software

Aug 2021 – Sep 2023

Polarion for internal teams is a unified application lifecycle management solution where you can define, build, test, and manage complex software systems. This tool serves 2,000+ developers, UX designers, QA, and PMs, increases velocity, accelerates deployments, and gives richer analytics on the entire software lifecycle

- Application Development Leadership: Led the design and implementation of a user-friendly interactive feature facilitating sprint planning for development teams, resulting in accelerated, well-organized, and highly accurate planning processes. This initiative contributed to a 50% improvement in accuracy and a 30% increase in development speed
- **Strategic Feature Engineering:** Developed and designed a user-stories prioritization feature utilizing the Weighted Shortest Job First method, with an innovative and intuitive UX that enhanced the company's ability to deliver optimal economic results
- **Cross-Org Collaboration:** Spearheaded the Siemens Startups forum, facilitating collaboration and innovative idea exchange, showcasing effective team collaboration and communication skills

Software Engineer, Google for Startups

Aug 2022 – Feb 2023

• **Empowerment App Design:** Designed an app for women in domestic violent relationships, so that they could move to a safer place for a couple of days and take care of themselves emotionally and strategically, achieving 3rd place among 2,000+ ideas

Software Engineer, milab - Media Innovation Lab

Jan 2021 – Jul 2021

• **Efficient Sensors Programming:** Utilized advanced **C++** techniques to optimize sensors and Arduino programming, improving real-time feedback in the prototype for a better user experience, highlighting fast-learning abilities

Master Sergeant, Israel Navy Submarines

Oct 2013 - Jun 2018

- **Team Leadership:** Commanded a skilled team of 12 soldiers through high-pressure scenarios in specialized missions, showcasing strong leadership under demanding conditions
- **Problem Solving:** Oversaw computers and sensors, installing and ensuring seamless operations and resolving technical issues for optimized system performance, demonstrating creative problem-solving skills and time management

CERTIFICATIONS

<u>Complete Web Development Bootcamp – Udemy:</u> Became a Full-Stack Web Developer <u>Python - The Practical Guide – Udemy:</u> Built my own Blockchain and Cryptocurrency

SAFe for Teams Course (5.1) – SCALED AGILE: Learned the skills to be a high-performing member of an Agile Release Train

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Computer Science, Reichman University, Herzliya, Israel

Oct 2019 - Nov 2022

- Completed a hands-on web app development course, building an end-to-end E-commerce web app with Node.js and React.js
- Certification studies in data science with Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Dev club: IMDb Web app, Kaggle competitions

VOLUNTEERING

Holocaust Survivors Fund: Supervised the food distribution operations for Holocaust survivors, demonstrating empathy and calm **Door2Dor:** Managed the supply chain of medical resources during COVID-19 for the elderly